Diego Thon Cortés

Front-End Developer

CONTACT

+ (56) 9 84137867

✓ diegothoncortes@gmail.com

SKILLS

JavaScript

Angular

ReactJS (Beginner)

Firebase

SCSS

Bootstrap

Angular Material

Tailwind (Beginner)

Git

Spanish (Native)

English (C1 Advanced)

CERTIFICATIONS

EF Standard English Test (EF SET)

ABOUT ME

Web developer, with 2 years and 9 months of experience in programming languages, tools and frameworks.

I'm currently working as a semi-senior programmer.

My experience includes Front-end development in web platform, using Scrum methodology.

About my skills I can remark the pro-activity, self-taught and very much wanting to learn new things within the IT area and the software development.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer (Soho)

6/2022 - Current

- Redesign of graphic interface for web platform proposed by the User (Gasco, Zurich,
- Usage of external API's to create online payment using providers such as Webpay and Zumpago.
- Keeping clean and documented code with low quantity of bugs in case of future changes and improvements.
- Used Flexbox and @Media only screen for responsiveness and adaptability before different viewports.
- Framework used: Angular 11+.
- Management of Jira and Kanban board for the tasks states and Confluence for documentation.
- Used Bitbucket for repositories.

Front-End Developer (Everis NTT DATA)

1/2021 - 6/2022

- Update and re-design of graphic interface on applications proposed by the user (LATAM Airlines - Alemana Clinic).
- Updating and creating new services and Http gueries for the usage of APIs.
- Keep clean and updated code for future changes.
- Using HTML, CSS and Bootstrap for various projects.
- Creation of the full DispoOnline Front-end Latam Project.
- Framework: Angular 8+.
- Management of Jira Kanban board for the detail of tasks.
- Management of BitBucket and GitLab repositories.

Software engineering (Pozo Almonte Municipal Corporation)

5/2019 - 12/2019

- Making of Web Application, focused in the sale of graveyard lands in Pozo Almonte.
- Programming language used for Backend C# .NET.
- Programming language used for Front-end Angular 7.
- Database Sql Server 2014.

EDUCATION

Inacap Valdivia, Chile (University)

Computer engineering, 2012 - 2018

2019 - Graduated

2019 - Licensed